<projects>
    <project>
        <title>
            Loan Default Prediction
        </title>
        <description>
            Created a web app, for getting predictions whether a loan applicant will default or not using their
            current loan details, and their previous loan details. The model testing is done using AUROC score.
        </description>
        <tech_stack>
            Python, Laravel, Angular, sklearn, LightGBM, XGBoost, tflearn, Jupyter Notebook.
        </tech_stack>
    </project>
    <project>
        <title>
            Medical Report Parser and Search
        </title>
        <description>
            Created a python OOP software which would take the folder path and its sub folders to find the medical
            reports to parse it into a semi-structured JSON format.
        </description>
        <tech_stack>
            Python, PHP, ElasticSearch, NLTK.
        </tech_stack>
    </project>
    <project>
        <title>
            IEEE-CIS Fraud Detection
        </title>
        <description>
            Predict whether the current transaction is fraudulent or not from the given transaction data. Achieved
            the accuracy score of 92.4989 % on test data.
        </description>
        <tech_stack>
            Python, Jupyter Notebook, sklearn, LightGBM, pandas, numpy.
        </tech_stack>
    </project>
    <project>
        <title>
            Music Year Prediction
        </title>
        <description>
            Predicting the year of Music release, from the sound features. Achieving Mean Absolute Error of 6.76016
            on test dataset.
        </description>
        <tech_stack>
            Python, tflearn, sklearn.
        </tech_stack>
    </project>
    <project>
        <title>
            Samyañc – My Spiritual Guru.
        </title>
        <description>
            Samyañc - My Spiritual Guru: `thelogicalkoan` is a closed domain question answering system for the spirituality domain, answering the question on the basis of the word-to-word English translated version of Shrimad Bhagavad Gita. The system uses Natural Language Processing and Understanding techniques with multiple data representations for fetching the answer. Several algorithms are designed to implement the system. Studied various research papers on NLP and QA Systems, thus selected and implemented the best fit for the system. The system is properly tested with different kinds of test cases to which it responds correctly.
        </description>
        <tech_stack>
            Python, PHP, XML-RPC, NLTK
        </tech_stack>
    </project>
    <project>
        <title>
            Matrix Library for C language
        </title>
        <description>
            I have tried to designed a matrix library for doing matrix related operations in C Language. There are still
            many operations left to be implemented.
        </description>
        <tech_stack>
            C
        </tech_stack>
    </project>
    <project>
        <title>
            Smart Alarm
        </title>
        <description>
            Smart Alarm is planned to be an Android Application which would follow the specific pattern to wake up
            the person at the right time, using the online perceptron learning algorithm.
        </description>
        <tech_stack>
            C++, Android
        </tech_stack>
    </project>
    <project>
        <title>
            What's Cooking
        </title>
        <description>
            Predict the cuisine from the list of ingredients. I achieved an accuracy of 76.758%
        </description>
        <tech_stack>
            Python, sklearn, pandas, numpy
        </tech_stack>
    </project>
</projects>
