<research>
    <research_paper>
        <title>
            FX OPTIMIZER: SUCCESSOR TO ADAM OPTIMIZER USING BATCH WISE MOVING AVERAGES.[ICLR 2018 submitted]
        </title>
        <abstract>
            The random distribution of the input data creates an imbalance in learning parameters, this causes some
            inputs’ patterns to be learned fast while others to be slow, and because of this, there is a subtle
            increase in the time the parameters takes to converge, this could be improved by storing the moving
            averages of the individual batches of the trainable variables. This lets the parameter update step to use
            the previous information about the same batch to update the parameters in the current batch. The paper
            presents an optimizer named Fx Optimizer, which is a first order optimizer, similar to ADAM Optimizer in
            the property but maintains the batch moving averages for each weight and converges faster and better than
            ADAM. This is shown experimentally on MNIST data-set. The intuition of the Optimizer comes from how the
            brain may take more or less time to learn different types of inputs from same class based on high or low
            complexity of input.
        </abstract>
        <link>
            https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/2ce7/b7d2599652a5b57f919a17977a5323a5c78b.pdf
        </link>
    </research_paper>
    <research_paper>
        <title>
            R-Algorithm
        </title>
        <abstract>
            R algorithm is an algorithm that is better than the naive string matching algorithm by 40-50%, and by same amount than KMP algorithm in worst case.
        </abstract>
        <link>
            Unpublished
        </link>
    </research_paper>
    <research_paper>
        <title>
            Predicting Age and Gender from Facial Images using CNN and Fine-Tuning Pre-trained models.[CVIP 2020 accepted]
        </title>
        <abstract>
            Predicting Age and Gender is a difficult task, in this work I ideated and created network architecture, created training methodologies and tricks including Feature Level and Score Level fusion to improve the result on Age and Gender prediction, the result being able to achieve SOTA level performance on both task on UTK Face database.
        </abstract>
        <link>
            https://cvip2020.iiita.ac.in/accepted.php#25
        </link>
    </research_paper>
</research>
